alright guys in this video I want to talk to you about the difference between
好的家伙在这个视频 我想 跟你说说两者之间的区别
a syntax error and an exception because whenever you're just trying to fix some
语法错误和异常，因为 无论什么时候你只是想修复一些
bugs in your program they kind of look like the same thing but there is a big
你的程序中的 bug 看起来很像 喜欢同样的事情， 但有一个很大的
difference between them and also how we can handle them or fix them in our
它们 之间的区别以及 如何还 我们 可以 处理它们或修复它们
program so let me make a very simple program right now what we're going to do
程序，以便让我做一个 很 简单的 节目现在我们要做 的
is we're going to let the user input um like a number so we'll just say what's
我们要让用户输入你 就像一个数字所以我们只会说出什么
your fave number so what this is going to do is it's going to display a little
你最喜欢的数字，所以这是怎么回事 做的是它 会显示 一个 小
prompt in the console whenever you run it and then the user types something in
运行时在控制台中提示 然后用户输入内容
and we store it in the variable tuna now what I want to do is I actually want to
我们现在将它存储在 变量金枪鱼中 我想做的是我真的想要
take that and convert it to an int because if they enter five we want to
把它转换成int 因为如果他们输入 五个我们想要的
make sure that Python doesn't treat that five is a string and actually converts
确保Python没有对待 那 五是一个字符串，实际上是转换
it to an int or an integer number now here's the problem that we may have
它为int或现在的整数 这是 我们可能遇到的问题
check this out let me just complete this real quick by
看一下这个 让我快速完成这个
printing out tuna see whenever you run this right now if the user enters
每当你跑步时打印出金枪鱼 现在， 如果用户输入
something like what's my favorite number 20 and hit enter it prints it out fine
喜欢什么是我最喜欢的号码 20 并点击 输入它打印出来就好了
but what if this happens well if the user decides to enter um
但是如果这种情况发生的话会怎么样呢 用户决定输入
dur and hit enter well then we have a little problem right here because you
dur和hit 进入然后我们 有一个 这个小问题因为你
can't convert dur to an integer so even though we didn't have any typos and this
不能转换 杜尔为整数所以 即使 虽然我们没有任何拼写错误
code looks fine right now an error still occurred because the user was an idiot
代码看起来很好， 现在仍然是一个错误 发生的原因是 用户是个白痴
so that's the difference between a syntax error annex and an exception whenever I say a syntax error that means
这就是a之间的区别 语法错误附件 和异常 每当我说一个语法错误意味着
a problem with your code so instead of writing input if you accidentally write imp in OOP of course that's a typo
你的代码有问题，而不是 如果你不小心写了，写输入 OOP中的 imp 当然 是一个错字
that's a syntax error so whenever you run this that's why it says invalid
这是一个语法错误， 所以每当你 运行这就是为什么它说无效
syntax whenever you see this it means hey dude you made a typo and again the
语法， 只要你看到它就意味着 嘿伙计，你做了一个错字，再次
other one
另一个
is called an exception and if we look down here we can see that we don't
被称为例外，如果我们看 在这里我们可以看到我们 没有
actually see the word exception anywhere some IDs may but this one doesn't we
实际上看到任何地方的单词异常 一些ID可能但是这个不是我们
actually see this it says value error now a value error is a special type of
实际上看到它说价值错误 现在值误差是一种特殊类型 的
an exception this means that okay when we try to
例外 这意味着当我们尝试时没关系
convert this to another value we had a problem and there are different type of
将此转换为我们拥有的另一个值 问题和 有 不同类型的
exceptions and I'm going to show you guys how to handle them right now so of
例外， 我要告诉你 伙计们现在如何处理它们
course whenever you're making our regular piece of software you want to
当然，无论你什么时候 做我们的 定期的软件要
allow for these problems to occur without breaking your entire program
允许发生 这些 问题 没有打破你的整个程序
because if the user is using this piece of software and they accidentally hit
因为如果用户正在 使用这件作品 他们不小心碰到了软件
the wrong key you don't want your program to crash like mine just did so
错误的 钥匙， 你不想要你的 程序崩溃 像我只是 这样 做
I'm going to show you guys a really cool way to deal with these exceptions on how
我要向你们 展示 一个非常酷的人 如何处理这些 例外的方式
you're supposed to so what I want to do is I want to make my entire example in arm while loop and whenever I write
你应该 这样我想要做的 我想把我的整个例子都写进去 循环时和我写的时候
while true this means that the loop is going to keep going on and on and on
虽然这是真的，这意味着循环是 要继续进行下去，并在和
forever until it breaks so not once not ten times just as many
永远直到 它破裂 所以没有一次不十倍正如 许多
times as we want it to and when we're finished we'll just break it so I'll show you guys the syntax of how to
倍， 我们希望它 和当我们 完成后我们会打破它，所以我会 展示你们的怎么语法
handle an exception now or pretty much just think of it whenever the user
现在或几乎处理异常 每当 用户想到它
messes something up that's a really simple way to explain it so what I'm
混淆了一些真的 解释它的简单方法，所以我是
going to do is I'm going to write the keyword try and then I'm going to add a
要做的就是我要写的 关键字尝试然后我要添加一个
colon and after that I'm going to type my code now this is the code that I
结肠，之后 我打算打字 我的代码 现在这 是我的代码
think that the user could possibly mess something up so instead of tuna actually
认为用户可能会搞乱 实际上是东西而不是金枪鱼
name is something good this time so int input
这个名字是好东西 所以int 输入
what's your fave number us so again this is the line of code right here that I
什么是你最喜欢的号码我们如此反复此 是我的代码行
think ok maybe we're going to get an error right here so I'm going to put this in a try is pretty much telling
想想也许我们会得到 一个 错误就 在这里，所以我 要放 这在尝试中 非常有说服力
your computer try to do this but if something goes wrong then we'll tell you
你的电脑尝试这样做，但如果 出现 问题然后我们会 告诉 你
what to do later so then I'll do something like take whatever they take
以后要做什么然后我会做 喜欢 拿走任何东西
whatever number they entered and take 18 divided by just because I don't know we
无论 他们输入的是 什么号码 ，都要18 除以因为我不知道 我们
just need something to do and then I'll break so this is what we hopefully want
只是需要做点什么 ，然后我会 这是我们希望的
to happen they're going to enter some number like 6 ok perfect no problems
要发生他们要 进入一些 数字像6 确定 完美无问题
it's going to say 18 divided by 6 which is 3 and it breaks so our program ends however we know from the previous
它会说18除以6 是3 ，它打破了 所以 我们的程序结束 但是我们从前面就知道了
example that they can mess something up they can enter something like derp or
例如 ，他们可以弄乱一些东西 他们可以输入像 derp或
they can enter I don't know maybe just some stupid symbols like this so we have to prepare for that without breaking our
他们可以进入我不知道也许只是 像这样的一些愚蠢的符号，所以我们有 针对 该 准备 不破坏 我们的
program so remember whenever they entered a word it can't convert it to an
程序所以每当他们都记得 输入一个单词， 它无法将其转换为
int and it was called a value error so what we're going to say is if you come across a value error right there then do
int 和它被称为值错误所以 我们要说的是，如果你来的话 然后在那里做一个值错误
this block of code right here and I hit caps lock so print arm will say like
这段代码就在这里， 我点击了 帽子锁定所以打印臂 会说像
don't say make sure and enter a number so basically what we have right here is
不要说确认并输入一个数字 所以我们在这里基本上就是这样
a very simple program to handle a very basic exception so saying first run this
一个非常简单的程序 来处理一个非常 基本的例外，所以先说这个
bit of code over and over and over again until the user finally gets it right now
的码位一遍 又一遍 又一遍 直到用户最终得到它
what we're going to do is we're going to allow them to enter a number and hopefully no problems work will occur
我们 要做的就是我们要做的 允许他们输入一个数字 和 希望不会出现问题
and we can break out of the loop however if we get a value error then what we can
然而 ， 我们可以摆脱 循环 如果我们得到一个价值错误，那么我们能做什么
do is just give them a nice little prompt on the screen and be
做就是给他们一个好小的 在屏幕上提示并且是
kay dude you got to try again so I'll show you guys how to do that right now
kay老兄，你得再试一次， 所以我会 告诉你们 现在该怎么做
so of course the first thing that always happens is whatever is in the try so it
所以当然 第一 件事 总是如此 发生的是 尝试中的 任何东西 ，所以它
tries to do this code right here without any problems whatsoever now if this
尝试在 这里 没有 做这个代码 如果这样，现在任何问题
actually works fine and they just enter 3 then it's going to print and skip this
实际上工作正常，他们 只是进入 3然后它将 打印并跳过此
so this block of code only executes if you indeed get an error so let me run
所以这个代码 块 只执行如果 你确实得到了一个错误让我跑
this and it says what's your favorite number house well if you had her like
这和它说你最喜欢的是什么 如果你有她喜欢的话很好
Bucky well then I said ok I tried to do this I got an error and then what I did
Bucky然后我说 好了我试着做 我得到了一个错误 ，然后我做了什么
is basically executed this code because it was value error so then it loops
基本上执行此代码是因为 这是价值错误， 所以它循环
again well what if your inner tuna nope do it again arm fart nope okay what
再好吧，如果你内心的 金枪鱼不 再做一次 手臂放屁好吧什么的
about 6 ok finally that works so finally we can do this and break out of the loop
大约6 好，终于可以 这么做了 我们可以做到这一点并打破循环
now of course a value error isn't the only type of an exception a value there
现在当然 值误差 不 只有一个例外类型的值
is basically when the enter when the user enters something that can't be
基本上当进入的时候 用户输入不可能的内容
converted to an integer well what if the user enters something like this all
转换为整数很好，如果 用户输入这样的东西
right what's your favorite number well what about zero ok that's a valid integer so let me hit enter what the
对你最喜欢的 号码 是什么 怎么样，这是有效的 整数所以让我点击进入什么
heck now we can another type and that's because of this whenever you take any
现在，我们可以使用另一种类型 因为这个， 每当 你 采取任何
number and divide it by zero you get another type of exception code as zero
数量和 除以 零 它 你 另一种类型的 异常代码 作为 零
division error so let me copy this and I'll show you guys how to handle other
分裂错误让我复制 这个和 我会告诉 你们 如何 处理 其他问题
errors as well so this exception happens whenever they enter string now a zero
错误以及 发生 此异常 每当他们输入字符串现在为零
division error basically says arm what can we say we'll say don't pick 0 so I'm
分裂错误基本上说臂什么的 我们可以说我们会说不要选0， 所以我
going to try this if they enter the string print this if they entered 0
如果他们进入 ，试试这个 字符串打印如果输入 0
print this and hopefully our program will work fine so what's your favorite
打印这个，希望我们的计划 会很好，所以 你最喜欢的 是什么
number house 0 don't pick 0 what about I don't know
号码屋 0 不要选择0我不 知道的是什么
fifty-four okay there we go now there's one other thing that I want to tell you guys and that is what if you just want
五十四好，我们现在去了 我要告诉你 一件事 伙计们，这就是你 想要的
to handle errors armed in general so you're going to say an exception might
处理一般的武装 错误 你会说一个例外
occur right here but I don't know if it's going to be value error I don't
发生在这里， 但我不知道是否 它不会是价值错误
know it's going to be a zero division error I just want a broad way to handle
知道这将是一个零分裂 错误我只想要一个广泛的方法来处理
every exception well in that instance you can just use the keyword except now
在那个例子中每个例外 你 现在可以使用关键字除外
99% of the time I'm going to recommend not to do this and this is why whenever you use accept it can hide a lot of your
的我要 推荐 99％的时间 不这样做，这就是为什么 每当 你 使用接受它可以隐藏 你 的 很多
problems so even though the user may enter something that's not valid you're
即使用户可能会出现问题 进入东西是无效的 你
going to go ahead and execute code anyways without really knowing on the
继续执行代码 无论如何都不知道
source of your problem so it's generally not a good idea to do this however you
你问题的根源一般都是这样 不管 你 做什么都不是个好主意
can pretty much this is what's going to happen I'll explain it this way it's
几乎可以这 是什么会 我会以 这种方式 解释 它
going to try to execute this code and if a problem occurs is first going to check
要 尝试执行这个代码，如果 出现问题时，首先要 检查
this one okay well it wasn't a Valliere then it's going to check this one well it wasn't a zero division error and then
这个好吧，这不是Valliere 然后它会 很好 地检查这一个 那不是零分错误
it's going to say okay well I'm just breaking out of your program so that's
它会说好的我只是 打破 你的程序 了 ，这样的
why it's not a good idea so that's what I accept does and that's why I don't
为什么这不是一个好 主意， 所以那是什么 我接受了， 这就是为什么我没有
like it now the one other thing that I want to tell you guys with exceptions
就像现在我的另一件事 想告诉你有例外的人
before I let you guys go is a keyword called finally so what finally is going
在我让你们 去之前 是一个 关键词 终于打电话了，最后是什么
to do is of course we have a couple options we're going to execute this or
要做的当然是我们有一对 我们将执行此 选项 或 选项
this or this or this now only one of these can execute per loop depending on
这个或这个或现在只有一个 这些可以依赖于每个循环执行
if the user didn't do anything wrong or if they did now what finally does is it basically says no matter if the code
如果用户没有做错什么或 如果他们现在做了什么，最后做的是它 基本上说无论代码如何
worked or if you got an exception then execute this line of code no matter what
工作或如果你有例外 执行这行代码不管是什么
so this is optional it's an optional line of code you can have that says
所以这是可选的，它是可选的 您可以拥有的代码行
execute this no matter what simple enough and what can we put we'll just
无论什么简单，执行此操作 足够了，我们可以把它放在什么地方
put loop complete so run it so if they entered a stupid
把循环完成 所以，如果他们进入了一个愚蠢的话，那就去吧
number or a stupid string and got an exception or they entered a real number
数字或愚蠢的字符串得到了 异常或他们输入一个实数
and it went fine no matter what the finally occurs every single time all
它都很好不管 是什么 终于每次都发生了
right so that's pretty much it with exceptions so whenever you think um the
是的，所以它 几乎 与 它 例外， 所以每当你 想到的时候
user can break your code or cause it caused an issue with your software then
用户可以破坏您的代码或导致它 然后 导致您的软件出现问题
put it in a try block now whenever you want to handle a specific type of
无论什么时候你都把它放在试块中 想要处理特定类型的
exception put except in that type now whenever you want to handle a general
现在除了那种类型之外的异常 每当你想要处理一般
exception and you don't really know how the user is going to mess it up and you can use accept and whenever you want a
例外，你真的不知道如何 用户会搞砸它和你 可以使用接受和随时随地
certain bit of code to execute no matter if the user had a user program correctly
无论如何 都要 执行某些代码 如果用户有正确的用户程序
or caused an issue then you can use finally so yes exceptions are kind of
或引起问题然后你可以使用 最后是的，例外情况就是这样
boring but they're necessary especially whenever we're making gooeys because well show you guys then so for now
无聊，但他们是 特别 必要的 每当我们做鬼脸的时候 那么现在你们好吧
thanks for watching don't forget to subscribe and we'll see you next video
谢谢观看 别忘 了 订阅，我们会 看到 你的 下一个视频